let's move to social science. And in particular, I want us to think about where is the potential for humanity and where we are now. And if you think about it, there's a big gap between where we think we could be and where we are, and it's in all kinds of areas. So let me ask you: How many of you in the last month have eaten more than you think you should? Just kind of general. OK. How many of you in the last month have exercised less than you think you should? OK, and for how many of you has raising your hands twice been the most exercise you got today? (Laughter) How many of you have ever texted while driving? OK, we're getting honest. Let's test your honesty. How many people here in the last month have not always washed your hands when you left the bathroom? (Laughter) A little less honest. By the way, it's interesting how we're willing to admit texting and driving but not washing our hands, that's difficult. (Laughter) We can go on and on. The problem, the topic is that there's lots of things when we know what we could do -- we could be very, very different, but we're acting in a very different way. And when we think how do we bridge that gap, the usual answer is, "Just tell people." For example, just tell people that texting and driving is dangerous. Did you know it's dangerous? You should stop doing it. You tell people something is dangerous, and they will stop. Texting and driving is one example. Another very sad example is that in the US, we spend between seven and eight hundred million dollars a year on what's called "financial literacy." And what do we get as a consequence of that? There was recently a study that looked at all the research ever to be conducted on financial literacy -- what's called a meta-analysis. And what they found is that when you tell people, you teach them financial literacy, they learn and they remember. But do people execute? Not so much. The improvement is about three or four percent immediately after the course, and then it goes down. And at the end of the day, the improvement is about 0.1 percent -- not zero, but as humanly close to zero as possible. (Laughter) So that's the sad news. The sad news is, giving information to people is just not a good recipe to change behavior. What is? Well, social science has made lots of strides, and the basic insight is that if we want to change behavior, we have to change the environment. The right way is not to change people, it's to change the environment. And I want to present a very simpleminded model of how to think about it: it's to think about behavioral change in the same way that we think about sending a rocket to space. When we think about sending a rocket to space, we want to do two main things. The first one is to reduce friction. We want to take the rocket and have as little friction as possible so it's the most aerodynamic possible. And the second thing is we want to load as much fuel as possible, to give it the most amount of motivation, energy to do its task. And behavior change is the same thing. So let's first talk about friction. In this particular case study I'll tell you about, there's a pharmacy, an online pharmacy. Imagine you go to your doctor. You have a long-term illness, your doctor prescribes to you a medication, you sign up for this online pharmacy and you get your medication in the mail every 90 days. Every 90 days, medication, medication, medication. And this online pharmacy wants to switch people from branded medication to generic medication. So they send people letters, and they say, "Please, please, please, switch to generics. You will save money, we will save money, your employer will save money." And what do people do? Nothing. So they try all kinds of things and nothing happens. So for one year, they give people an amazing offer. They send people a letter, and they say, "If you switch to generics now, it will be free for a whole year." Free for a whole year. Amazing! What percentage of people do you think switched? Less than 10 percent. At this point, they show up to my office. And they come to complain. Why did they pick me? I wrote a couple of papers on the "allure of free." In those papers, we showed that if you reduce the price of something for, let's say, 10 cents to one cent, nothing much happens. You reduce it from one cent to zero, now people get excited. (Laughter) And they said, "Look, we read these papers on 'free,' we gave 'free.' Not working as we expected. What's going on?" I said, "You know, maybe it's a question of friction." They said, "What do you mean?" I said, "People are starting with branded. They can do nothing and end with branded. To move to generic, they have to choose generic over branded, but they also have to do something. They have to return the letter." So this is what we call a "confounded design." Two things are happening at the same time. It's branded versus generic, but it's doing nothing versus doing something. So I said, "Why don't we switch it? Why don't we send people a letter and say, 'We're switching you to generics. You don't need to do anything. If you want to stay with branded, please return the letter.'" (Laughter) Right? What do you think happened? Lawyers, lawyers happened. (Laughter) It turns out, this is illegal. By the way, for brainstorming and creativity, doing things that are illegal and immoral, it's fine, as long as it's just in the brainstorming phase. (Laughter) But this was the purity of the idea, because the initial design was the branded had the no-action benefit. In my illegal, immoral design, generic had the no-action benefit. But they agreed to give people a T-intersection: send people a letter and say, "If you don't return this letter, we will be forced to stop your medications. But when you return the letter, you could choose branded at this price, generic at this price." Now people had to take an action. They were on even footing. Right? It wasn't that one had the no-action benefit. What percentage do you think switched? The vast majority switched. So what does it tell us? Do people like generics, or do we like branded? We hate returning letters. (Laughter) This is the story of friction: small things really matter. And friction is about taking the desired behavior and saying: Where do we have too much friction so it's slowing people down from acting on it? And every time you see that the desired behavior and the easy behavior are not aligned, it means we want to try and realign them. That's the first part. We talked about friction. Now let's talk about motivation. In this particular study, we were trying to get very poor people in a slum called Kibera in Kenya to save a little bit of money for a rainy day. You know, if you're very, very poor, you have no extra money, you live hand to mouth, and from time to time, bad things happen. And when something bad happens, you have nothing to draw on, you borrow. The Kibera people can borrow at sometimes up to 10 percent interest a week. And then, of course, it's really hard to get out of it. You live hand to mouth, something bad happens, you borrow, things get worse and worse and worse. So we wanted people to keep a little bit of money for a rainy day. And we thought about what is the motivation, what is the fuel that we need to add? And we tried all kinds of things. Some people, we texted them once a week and said, "Please try to save 100 shillings" -- about a dollar -- "this week." Some people, we sent a text message as if it came from their kids. So it said, "Hi Mom, hi Dad, this is little Joey" -- whatever the name of the kid was -- "Try and save 100 shillings this week for the future of our family." Right? I'm Jewish, a little bit of guilt always works. (Laughter) Some people got 10 percent. "Save up to a hundred shillings, we'll give you 10 percent." Some people got 20 percent. Some people got also 10 percent and 20 percent, but they got it with loss aversion. What is loss aversion? Loss aversion is the idea that we hate losing more than we enjoy gaining. Now, think about somebody who is in a 10-percent condition and they put 40 shillings in. They put 40 shillings, we give them four more, they say thank you very much. That person gave up six. They could have gotten six more if they gave a hundred, but they don't see it. So we created what we call pre-match. We put the 10 shillings in at the beginning of the week. We said, "It's waiting for you!" And then if somebody puts 40 in, we say, "Oh, you put 40 in, we're leaving four, and we're taking six back." So in both cases, pre-match or post-match, people get 10 percent. But in the pre-match, they see the money they did not match leaving their account. So we have text, text from kids, 10 percent, 20 percent, pre-match, post-match. And we had one more condition. It was a coin about this size, with 24 numbers written on it. And we asked them to put the coin somewhere in their hut, and every week, take a knife and scratch the number for that week -- week one, two, three, four -- scratch it like a minus if they didn't save and scratch it up and down if they saved. Now, think to yourself: Which one of those methods do you think worked the best? Text, text from the kids, 10 percent, 20 percent, beginning of the week, end of the week, and the coin? I'll tell you what the average people think. We've done these studies of prediction, both in the US and in Kenya. People think that 20 percent will get a lot of action, 10 percent less, the rest of it will do nothing -- kids, coin, doesn't matter. People think loss aversion will have a small effect. What actually happened? Sending a text reminder once a week helps a lot. Good news! This program lasted six months. People forget. Reminding people is great. Ten percent at the end of the week helped some more. Financial incentives work. Twenty percent at the end of the week -- just like 10 percent, no difference. Ten percent in the beginning of the week helps some more. Loss aversion works. Twenty percent in the beginning of the week, just like 10 percent in the beginning of the week, no difference. And the text message from the kids was just as effective as 20 percent plus loss aversion -- which is amazing, right? It's amazing how motivating messages from kids were. And one conclusion is we don't use kids enough. (Laughter) And, of course, I don't mean in a child labor sense. But if you think about parents and their kids, we are the best that we can for our kids, and we think about the future, and I think we should think about how to use that amazing source of motivation to get parents to behave in a better way. But the big surprise of this study was the coin. The coin basically doubled savings compared to everything else. And now the question is: Why? What was it about the coin? So I'll tell you how I started thinking about the coin, and then we'll come back to it. So you know, when I do research on, let's say, buying coffee, I don't need to go anywhere. I can sit in my office. I've bought enough coffee. I know how it works. The details, I'm familiar with. When you do research in some of the poorest places in the world, you have to go and visit and see what's going on and get some insight about how the system works. And on that particular day, I'm in a place called Soweto in South Africa, and I'm sitting in a place that sells funeral insurance. You know, in the US people spend crazy amounts of money on weddings? In South Africa, it's funerals. People spend up to a year or two years of income on funerals. And I sit in this place -- by the way, before you judge the South Africans as being irrational with this, I just want to remind you that spending a lot of money on funerals compared to weddings, at least you know for sure you only have one. (Laughter)
pasemos a las ciencias sociales. Y en particular, quiero que pensemos dónde está el potencial para la humanidad y dónde estamos ahora. Y si lo piensan, hay una gran brecha entre donde creemos que podríamos estar y donde estamos, y eso se da en todas las áreas. Así que déjenme que les pregunte: ¿Cuántos de Uds. en el último mes han comido más de lo debido? Solo en general. Bien. ¿Cuántos de Uds. en el último mes han hecho menos ejercicio del que creen que deberían? ¿Y para cuántos de Uds. que han levantado las manos dos veces es la mayor cantidad de ejercicio que han hecho hoy? (Risas) ¿Cuántos de Uds. han enviado mensajes de texto mientras conducían? Estamos siendo honestos. Probemos su honestidad. ¿Cuántas personas aquí en el último mes no siempre se han lavado las manos al salir del baño? (Risas) Un poco menos honesto. Es interesante cómo estamos dispuestos a admitir enviar mensajes y conducir pero no el de no lavarnos las manos, eso es difícil. (Risas) Podemos seguir y seguir. El problema, el tema es que hay muchas cosas que sabemos sobre lo que podemos hacer. Podríamos ser muy diferentes, pero actuamos de manera muy diferente. Y cuando pensamos cómo cerrar esa brecha, la respuesta habitual es: "Solo díselo a la gente". Por ejemplo, diga a la gente que enviar mensajes y conducir es peligroso. ¿Saben que es peligroso? Deberían dejar de hacerlo. Dices a la gente que algo es peligroso y se detendrán. Enviar mensajes de texto y conducir es un ejemplo. Otro ejemplo muy triste es que en EE. UU. gastamos entre USD 780 millones al año en lo llamado "educación financiera". ¿Y qué obtenemos como consecuencia de eso? Recientemente un estudio analizó toda la investigación que se ha realizado sobre educación financiera: lo que se llama un metanálisis. Y lo que encontraron es que cuando dices a la gente, que les enseñas educación financiera, ellos aprenden y recuerdan. ¿Pero la gente lo lleva a cabo? No tanto. La mejora es de un 3 o 4 %, inmediatamente después del curso, y luego baja Y al final, la mejora es de un 0,1 %, no cero, sino tan humanamente cercano a cero como sea posible. (Risas) Esa es la triste noticia. La triste noticia es que dar información a la gente no es una buena receta para cambiar el comportamiento. ¿Qué es? Las ciencias sociales han avanzado mucho, y la idea básica es que, si queremos cambiar el comportamiento, tenemos que cambiar el entorno. La forma correcta no es cambiar a las personas, sino el entorno, Y quiero presentar un modelo muy simple de cómo pensarlo: Pensar en el cambio de comportamiento de la misma manera que pensamos en enviar un cohete al espacio. Cuando pensamos en enviar un cohete al espacio, queremos hacer dos cosas principales. Primero, reducir la fricción. Queremos que el cohete tenga la menor fricción posible, así que hay que hacerlo lo más aerodinámico posible. Y segundo, queremos cargar la mayor cantidad de combustible posible, para dar la mayor cantidad de motivación y energía para hacer su tarea. Y para el cambio de comportamiento es lo mismo. Entonces, primero hablemos de la fricción. En este caso de estudio en particular les hablaré sobre una farmacia en línea. Imagina, vas al médico. Tienes una enfermedad de larga duración. Tu médico te receta un medicamento, te registras en esta farmacia en línea y recibes el medicamento por correo cada 90 días. Cada 90 días, medicación, medicación, medicación. Y esta farmacia en línea quiere hacer cambiar a las personas de medicamentos de marca a medicamentos genéricos. Entonces envían cartas a las personas diciendo: "Por favor, cambie a genéricos. Ahorrará dinero, ahorraremos dinero, su empleador ahorrará dinero". ¿Y qué hace la gente? Nada. Entonces prueban todo tipo de cosas y no pasa nada. Entonces, durante un año, ofrecen a la gente una oferta increíble. Le envían una carta a la gente que dice: "Si cambia a genéricos ahora, los tendrá gratis durante todo un año". Gratis por todo un año. ¡Asombroso! ¿Qué porcentaje de personas creen que cambió? Menos del 10 %. En este punto, se presentan a mi oficina. Y vienen a quejarse. ¿Por qué me eligieron? Escribí un par de artículos sobre el "encanto de la libertad". En esos artículos, mostramos que, si se reduce el precio de algo digamos, de 10 centavos a 1 centavo, no pasa mucho. Lo reducen de 1 centavo a 0, la gente se emociona. (Risas) Y dijeron: "leemos estos documentos 'gratis', los dimos 'gratis'. No funciona como esperábamos. ¿Que está pasando?" Y dije: "Tal vez es una cuestión de fricción". Y preguntaron: "¿Qué quieres decir?" Y dije: "La gente comienza con la marca. No pueden hacer nada y termina consumiendo la marca. Para pasar a genérico, tienen que elegir genérico en lugar de marca, pero también tienen que hacer algo. Tienen que contestar la carta". Así que esto es lo que llamamos un "diseño confuso". Dos cosas suceden al mismo tiempo. Es marca versus genérico, y no hacer nada versus hacer algo. Y dije: "¿Por qué no lo cambiamos? ¿Por qué no enviamos una carta a la gente y decimos: "Te estamos cambiando a genéricos. No necesitas hacer nada. Si desea seguir recibiendo la marca, responda la carta". (Risas) ¿Sí? ¿Qué creen qué pasó? Pues, abogados y más abogados. (Risas) Resulta que esto es ilegal. Por cierto, para la lluvia de ideas y la creatividad, hacer cosas ilegales e inmorales está bien, siempre y cuando sea solo en la fase de lluvia de ideas. (Risas) Pero esta era la pureza de la idea porque el diseño inicial era que la marca tenía el beneficio de la no acción. En mi diseño ilegal e inmoral, el genérico tenía el beneficio de no actuar. Pero acordaron darle a la gente una intersección en T: enviar una carta a la gente diciendo: "Si no responde esta carta nos veremos obligados a suspender sus medicamentos. Pero cuando responda la carta, puede elegir la marca a este precio, o el genérico a este precio". Ahora la gente tenía que actuar. Estaban en igualdad de condiciones. ¿Sí? No era que uno tuviera el beneficio de no actuar. ¿Qué porcentaje creen que cambió? La gran mayoría cambió. Y esto, ¿qué nos muestra? ¿A la gente nos gustan los genéricos o las marcas? Odiamos responder cartas. (Risas) Esta es la historia de la fricción: las cosas pequeñas realmente importan. Y la fricción trata de analizar el comportamiento deseado preguntando: ¿Dónde tenemos demasiada fricción frenamos a la gente de actuar en consecuencia? Y cada vez que uno ve que el comportamiento deseado y el comportamiento fácil no están alineados, significa que queremos intentar realinearlos. Esa es la primera parte. Hablamos de fricción. Ahora hablemos de motivación. En este estudio particular, intentábamos reunir gente muy pobre de un barrio pobre llamado Kibera en Kenia para que ahorraran algo de dinero para el tiempo de vacas flacas. ¿Saben? Si eres muy, muy pobre, no tienes dinero extra, vives con una mano delante y otra atrás, y de vez en cuando pasan cosas malas. Y cuando sucede algo malo, no tienes nada a qué recurrir y lo pides prestado. Un préstamo en Kibera puede significar hasta un 10 % de interés por semana. Y luego, por supuesto, es realmente difícil salir de eso. Vives con una mano delante y otra atrás, pasa algo malo, pides prestado el dinero y entonces las cosas empeoran y empeoran. Queríamos que la gente ahorrara un poco de dinero para las malas rachas. Y pensamos en cuál podría ser la motivación, y qué combustible necesitábamos agregar. Y probamos todo tipo de cosas. A algunas personas, les enviamos SMS una vez a la semana diciéndoles: "Por favor, intente ahorrar 100 chelines -- alrededor de un dólar -- esta semana". A algunas personas, enviamos un SMS como si viniera de sus hijos. Y decía: "Hola mamá, hola papá, soy Joey" -- cualquiera que fuese el nombre del niño -- "Intenta ahorrar 100 chelines esta semana para el futuro de nuestra familia". ¿Sí? Soy judío, un poco de culpa siempre funciona. (Risas) Algunas personas ahorraron el 10 %. "Ahorre hasta cien chelines, le daremos un 10 %". Algunas personas ahorraron el 20 % Algunas personas también ahorraron el 10 % y 20 % pero lo lograron por aversión a la pérdida. ¿Qué es la aversión a la pérdida? La aversión a la pérdida es que odiamos más la idea de perder que lo que disfrutamos ganar. Piensen en alguien que está en una situación del 10 % y juega 40 chelines. Juega 40 chelines, le damos 4 más, dice muchas gracias. Esa persona renunció a 6. Podría haber obtenido 6 más si hubiera jugado 100, pero no lo ve. Y creamos lo que llamamos pre-juego. Pusimos los 10 chelines al comienzo de la semana. Dijimos: "¡Te está esperando!" Y luego, si alguien pone 40, decimos: "Pones 40, dejamos 4 y recuperamos 6". Entonces, en ambos casos, pre-juego o post-juego, la persona recupera el 10 %. Pero en el pre-juego ve que el dinero que no jugó sale de su cuenta. Entonces teníamos los SMS, los SMS de los hijos, 10 %, 20 %, pre-juego, post-juego. Y teníamos una condición más. Era una moneda de este tamaño, con 24 números escritos en ella. Y les pedimos que pusieran la moneda en algún lugar de su cabaña, y que cada semana con un cuchillo rascaran el número de esa semana semana 1, 2, 3, 4, que rascaran un signo negativo, si no ahorraron y que rascaran arriba y abajo, si sí ahorraron. Ahora, piensen: ¿Cuál de esos métodos creen que funcionó mejor? El SMS, el SMS de los hijos, el 10 %, el 20 %, al principio de la semana, el fin de semana o la moneda? Les diré lo que piensa la gente promedio. Hemos hecho estos estudios de predicción, tanto en EE. UU. como en Kenia. La gente piensa que el 20 % tendrá mucha aceptación, el 10 % menos, y el resto no tendrá nada de aceptación: hijos, moneda, nada de eso importa. La gente piensa que la aversión a la pérdida tendrá un pequeño efecto. Pero ¿qué pasó realmente? Enviar un SMS recordatorio una vez por semana ayuda mucho. ¡Buenas noticias! Este programa duró 6 meses. La gente olvida. Recordar a la gente es genial. El 10 % al final de la semana ayudó un poco más. Los incentivos financieros funcionan. El 20 % al final de la semana, al igual que el 10 %, no genera diferencia. El 10 % al comienzo de la semana ayuda un poco más. La aversión a la pérdida funciona. El 20 % al comienzo de la semana, al igual que el 10 % al comienzo de la semana, no genera diferencia. Y el SMS de los hijos fue igual de efectivo que el 20 % más aversión a la pérdida. Lo cual es asombroso, ¿verdad? Es sorprendente lo motivadores que fueron los mensajes de los hijos. Y una conclusión es que no usamos a los hijos lo suficiente. (Risas) Y, por supuesto, no me refiero en un sentido de trabajo infantil. Pero si piensan en los padres y sus hijos, somos lo mejor que podemos para nuestros hijos, y pensamos en el futuro. Y creo que deberíamos pensar cómo usar esa increíble fuente de motivación para que los padres se comporten de mejor manera. Pero la gran sorpresa de este estudio fue la moneda. La moneda básicamente duplicó los ahorros en comparación con todo lo demás. Y ahora la pregunta es: ¿por qué? ¿De qué trataba la moneda? Les diré cómo empecé a pensar en la moneda y luego volveremos a eso. Cuando investigo, digamos, mientras me compro un café, no necesito ir a ningún lado, me puedo sentar en mi oficina. He comprado suficiente café. Sé cómo funciona. Estoy familiarizado con los detalles. Cuando investigas en algunos de los lugares más pobres del mundo, tienes que ir allí y ver qué pasa y hacerte una idea de cómo funciona el sistema. Y en ese día en particular, estaba en un lugar llamado Soweto en Sudáfrica, sentado en un lugar que vendía seguros funerarios. ¿Saben que en EE. UU. la gente gasta grandes sumas de dinero en bodas? En Sudáfrica en funerales. Las personas gastan hasta uno o dos años de ingresos en funerales. Y sentado en este lugar -- por cierto, antes de juzgar a los sudafricanos de irracionales por esto, solo quiero recordarles que gastar mucho dinero en funerales en comparación con bodas, al menos uno logra la certeza que solo será uno -- (Risas)
OK, so I sit in this place that sells funeral insurance. And this guy comes in with his son -- his son is about 12 -- and he buys funeral insurance for a week. It will cover 90 percent of his funeral expense only if he dies in the next seven days. Right? These are very poor people, they buy small amounts of insurance and small amount of soap and such. And he gets that certificate, and in a very ceremonious way, he gives it to his son. And as he gives it to his son, I think to myself, why the ceremony? What is this father doing? Now, think about the breadwinner that decides on that particular day to direct some money into insurance or savings. What is the family going to see tonight? They're going to see less. Right? At that level of poverty, there'll be less food, less kerosene, less water -- something less tonight. And what his father was doing and what our coin was trying to do is to say, yes, there's less food on the table, but there's another activity. You see, what happened is, there are many good, important economic activities, like savings and insurance, that are invisible. And now the question is: How do we make them visible? So let's go back to our rocket model. We have to, first of all, look at the system and see where there's little things we can fix, with friction, where is there that we can remove friction? And then the next thing we want to do is to think broadly about the system, and say: What other motivations can we bring in? And that's a much more difficult exercise, and we don't always know what would work best. Is it going to be money? Is it going to be loss aversion? Is it going to be something that is visible? We don't know, and we have to try different things. We also have to realize that our intuition sometimes misleads us. We don't always necessarily know what would work the best. So if we think about this gap between where we could be and where we are, it's a really sad thing to see this gap and to think about it. But the good news is, there's lots we can do. Some of the changes are easy, some of the changes are more complex. But if we'll attack each problem directly, not by just providing more information to people but trying to change the friction, add motivation, I think we can ... Can we close the gap? No. But can we get much better? Absolutely, yes. Thank you very much. (Applause)
Bien, entonces sentado en este lugar que vendía seguros funerarios, este tipo entra con su hijo, su hijo tiene unos 12 años, y compra un seguro funerario por una semana. Cubrirá el 90 % de sus gastos funerarios solo si muere en los próximos siete días. ¿Sí? Estas son personas muy pobres, compran pequeñas cantidades de seguro y una pequeña cantidad de jabón y tal. Y él consigue ese certificado, y de una manera muy ceremoniosa, se lo da a su hijo. Y mientras se lo da a su hijo, pienso para mí, ¿por qué tanta ceremonia? ¿Qué está haciendo este padre? Ahora, piense en el sostén de la familia que decide ese día en particular invertir algo de dinero en seguros o ahorros. ¿Qué va a ver la familia esta noche? Van a ver menos. ¿Sí? En ese nivel de pobreza, habrá menos comida, menos queroseno, menos agua... algo menos esa noche. Y lo que hacía su padre y lo que nuestra moneda trataba de hacer es decir, sí, hay menos comida en la mesa, pero hay otra actividad. Lo que sucedió es que hay muchas actividades económicas buenas e importantes, como ahorros y seguros, que son invisibles. Y ahora la pregunta es: ¿cómo las hacemos visibles? Así que volvamos a nuestro modelo de cohete. Tenemos que, antes de nada, mirar el sistema y ver dónde hay pequeñas cosas que podemos arreglar, con fricción, ¿Dónde podemos eliminar la fricción? Y luego, lo siguiente es pensar ampliamente sobre el sistema, y preguntarnos: ¿Qué otras motivaciones podemos aportar? Y ese es un ejercicio mucho más difícil, y no siempre sabemos qué funcionaría mejor. ¿Será dinero? ¿Será la aversión a la pérdida? ¿Será algo visible? No lo sabemos y tenemos que probar cosas diferentes. También tenemos que darnos cuenta de que nuestra intuición a veces nos engaña. No siempre sabemos necesariamente qué funcionaría mejor. Entonces, si pensamos en esta brecha entre donde podríamos estar y donde estamos, es realmente triste ver esta brecha y pensar en ello. Pero la buena noticia es que hay muchas cosas que podemos hacer. Algunos de los cambios son fáciles, algunos son más complejos. Pero si atacamos cada problema directamente, no solo proporcionando más información a las personas, sino tratando de cambiar la fricción y agregando motivación, Creo que podemos... ¿Podemos cerrar la brecha? No. ¿Pero podemos mejorar mucho? Absolutamente que sí. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)